ARINDAM SAHA, Programmer Analyst

+91-8317349840 | arindam.as80@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Kolkata, India

AREA OF INTEREST

Passionate about using real-world evidence (RWE) to drive meaningful insights in health economics and outcomes research (HEOR). I aim to analyze patient data, claims, and EHRs to assess treatment outcomes and costs, with a focus on applying advanced analytics and machine learning for better healthcare decisions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology and Solutions India Private Limited

Programmer Analyst

Jul 2022 – present

Spearheading data integration initiatives with Qlik Replicate, ensuring data integrity and quality through advanced ETL processes for US-based clients.

• ABS Clinical Solutions

Consultant Scientific Writer (Part-time)

Jul 2022 - present

Helping customers to prepare clear, concise, and high-quality of reports and documents for regulatory submissions, and publications in international peer-reviewed medical journals.

• Micro Labs Limited, Bangalore, India

Industrial Trainee

Oct 2019 - Nov 2019

Acquired training in Manufacturing and Packaging of tablets, capsules & topicals, Environmental Health & Safety, Quality Control, and Engineering department.

SKILLS

- **Programming Skills**: Python, R, SQL, MySQL
- **BI tools**: Power BI, Tableau, Qlik Replicate, KNIME. Qlik Sense
- Relevant Courses: Machine Learning, EDA, Data Science, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Model Building and
 Development, Data Extraction, Business Report, Statistical Analysis, Statistical Modeling, Data Structures, Data Imputation,
 Model Tuning, Regression Model, Classification Model, Decision Tree, KNN, Naïve Bayes, Random Forest, Bagging,
 Boosting, Neural Network Analysis, Inferential Statistics, Data Collection, Feature Engineering.

EDUCATION

• University of Texas at Austin and Great Lakes Institute, India

Post-Graduation Program (Data Science and Business Analytics) cGPA: 3.94/4.5

Apr 2024 - present

• National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER), S. A. S. Nagar, Mohali, India

M.S. Pharm (Medicinal Chemistry)

Nov 2020 - Jun 2022

cGPA: 9.92/10 (Placed among the top 5% of candidates)

• Rajiv Gandhi University of Health Sciences, Karnataka, India

Bachelor of Pharmacy (B. Pharm)

Aug 2016 - Nov 2020

Cumulative Percentile: 79.78

PROJECTS

- Austo Automobile Analysis: Exploratory Data Analysis
- OTT Media Service Provider: Linear Regression
- Hypothesis Testing: Inferential Statistics
- Hotel Booking Analysis: ML (Decision Tree, KNN, Naïve Bayes)
- Easy Visa: ML (Bagging, Boosting, Hyper Parameter Tuning, Ensemble)

ARINDAM SAHA, Programmer Analyst

+91-8317349840 | arindam.as80@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Kolkata, India

- All Life Bank Market Penetration: Unsupervised Learning
- New Wheels Sales Analysis: SQL
- ABC Estate Wines: Time Series Forecasting
- Insurance Claim Analysis: Tableau
- Market Sales for Products Dashboard: Power BI

CERTIFICATIONS

• Completed online course in "Fundamentals of Health Economics and Outcomes Research	Nov 2023
(HEOR)", offered by MarksMan Academy of Health Sciences	
• Completed online course in "The Art and Science of Searching in Systematic Reviews",	Aug 2023
offered by edX (founded by Harvard and MIT)	
 <u>Certified</u> as "Power BI Data Analyst Associate - PL-300", exam conducted by Microsoft 	Jan 2023
• Completed online course on "Oracle 12c Database Administration", offered by Udemy	Jun 2023
• Completed online course on "Microsoft Power BI Desktop for Business Intelligence",	Sep 2022
offered by Maven Analytics in Udemy	
• Completed online course on "The Advance SQL Course", offered by Udemy,	Sep 2022
• Completed online course on "Python", offered by Centre for Continuing Education,	Nov 2021
IIT Madras Digital Skills Academy's Programme, GUVI	
• Completed online course on "Excel for Beginners", offered by Great Learning Academy	Oct 2021

PATENTS

• Roy S, Das S, Das K, <u>Saha A</u>, Mukherjee D, Bose A, Parashar A, Dara C, Sarkar S, Mondal S. Instrument for Liposomal Drug Delivery for the Treatment of Parkinson's Disease. Intellectual Property Rights (IPR), UK Design Number- <u>6346294</u>, Filed: 12.02.2024. Granted: 21.02.2024.

SCHOLARSHIP, HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recipient of the **National Testing Agency** (**NTA**) PG scholarship for qualifying the all-India level Graduate Pharmaceutical Aptitude Test (GPAT 2020) with **95.88 percentile score** all over India, among 50,000+ candidates.
- Qualified for the National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research Joint Entrance Exam (NIPER JEE 2020) with all India rank 595 among 10,000+ candidates.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER), S. A. S. Nagar, Mohali, India

- Class Representative (2020 2022)
- Head of Alumni Association (2021 2022)
- Member of Mess Management Committee (Regulation / Quality control of food served at housing facilities)
- Member of Placement Cell Committee (2021 2022)

Acharya & B.M. Reddy College of Pharmacy, Bengaluru, India

- Volunteered for Swachh Bharat Abhiyan (Cleaning India Mission), a national-level campaign by the Government of India
- Industrial Visit Coordinator in Cipla, Goa (December 2019)
- Class Representative (2017 2018)